♪ [music] ♪
[crowd cheering]
*[Gil Guillory] Fighting is as old as,
as human kind has ever been.*
*Something about beating another man,*
*into submission,*
*that the world is attracted to.*
*What is it?*
Man is the only species on earth,
outside of its natural environment.
And what society has caused to do
is take out a couple of different things
out of the equation. The first is.
The rules of man.
The rules of man suggest
that man is a warrior.
*By nature he's a warrior
so when you say, "Fight"!*
*Everyone's gonna turn and look.
Everyone.*
*"Fighting is truth"*
[clapping and drumming]
♪ [music] ♪
[crowd cheering]
*[Gil] Very few men
will actually walk the aisles.*
*And get into that combat arena*
*And very few men
will do it 20 to 30 times.*
*Most of these guys
have fight they'll never fight again.*
*They've think they can do it,
they want to do it.*
*They want everybody to know
that they're cage fighters.*
*But when that door close in,
you'd hear that lock "click"!*
*And when it's time to go*
*And that guy looks at you
across the cage.*
*And you can't give him
the same look that he gave you.*...
*Now you know you're in trouble.*
*Every fight has a story
thats yet to be played out.*
*As a match maker,
I have to imagine that story.*
*I have to write the script of that story.*
*What would happen?*
*If you were in your tribe, I was in my tribe *
*And we came across each other.
What would happen?*
*Beside bashing each other
in the head with a rock.*
*Let's throw it outta there*
*This is what "Combat" is*
*It's not two men standing up. *
*And just punching each other
in the head and stomach.*
*Combat encompasses everything.*
*Do what you can to win a fight.*
[crowd yelling]
[thud, thud, thud]
[horn blowing]
[crowd cheering and clapping]
*We're bringing back
the pure essence of combat.*
♪ [music] ♪
[crowd cheering and clapping]
*I can take any man.
And I'll make him a star.*
- [*DUSTIN POIRIER*]
*My dream is to be...*
*The best fighter.*
*At a 155 lbs in the world*
Fighting is what I do.
My father was a fighter.
My grandfather was a fighter.
It's just in my blood.
[punching]
What we're doing on this local level is,
We take these young guys,
We're developing them.
So that they can gradually progress,
To the big leagues.
So, we are. In essence,
a minor league mixed martial arts.
We're a feeder to UFC, Strike force, DREAM.
But they won't get to the big time.
If we don't have these shows.
We have to have these shows.
Fans have to support us.
In order to get our local guys
to the next level.
Those with talent.
- When I first started fighting,
The sport of fighting.
I didn't even expect to,
I had no, not one thought of money.
Or fame or anything like that
on my mind.
And I just wanted to fight, that's it,
Simple and plain.
I called the place.
And I ask them.
So I said, If come over here and train,
Will I be able to fight?
Really, against other opponents?
And they said "Yeah, you will"
I was there the next day.
[train honking]
[thud,thud,thud]
♪ [music] ♪
- [Tim] *Defend! Defend! *
- * I'm stuck.*
* I know, come the other way!
Come this way, come to me!*
Defend!
*Don't get knocked out right here.*
*There you go...*
* Feet on the wall, push away.*
*Flip! Flip! Flip!*
♪ [music] ♪
*[alarm ringing]*
- *Stop. It's not your skill, its not yours.*
- *There's a music playing, this is Tim*
-["Crazy" Tim Credeur] What
we're doing today with MMA,
and with mixed martial arts.
Is what martial arts was always
suppose to be.
And the revitalization of martial arts
in America is starting to happen.
The reality of martial arts through MMA
Has been boiled down to, whats true
and whats just crazy.
What's crazy movie stuff.
*There's no 7 year old
black belts over here. That's not real.*
*We don't have 5 year olds doing
flying jump kicks, through the walls.*
That's just not the reality of it.
[swoosh, swoosh]
These guys who've done
these traditional martial arts,
In these traditional martial arts school
They can't win a fight in an MMA match.
How can that be possible?
If you spent 20 years
in a martial arts academy.
*You've been doing kata's
and breaking fake boards.*
*And wearing funny belts.*
*You haven't been training
to be a fighter.*
*You've been training
to go be in bar and belly circus.*
That's not martial arts,
That's crazy talk, that's ridiculous.
When martial arts was developed
for samurais and for the warriors
of the warrior caste in Asia,
you know, people fell off.
And those people
that did not get to become samurais.
They did not get to become warriors.
Those people got to become farmers.
To make it for everyone,
like I've said before,
is to make it not what it really is.
[thud, thud, thud]
- *[male voice] Don't leave any blood
splattered on that sink.*
*Or on the tank. Go wash yourself off.*
*And then wash your area off too, okay?*
Okay? That's like a health violation, ok
- *[Tim] Okay guys, look too, that's a good point.*
Health inspector came
and there was some blood,
and he was pissed you know,
he didn't say much..
But if you bleed or somethin' like that,
make sure you clean your stuff up.
Don't leave blood all over the place,
it just make us look ridiculous.
We're suppose to be a martial arts school.
Help me, Help you
♪ [music] ♪
- *[Gil] You know I grew up,
watching men who work hard.*
*Who party hard and on
a Friday or Saturday night.*
They weren't scared to fight hard.
*What we're trying to do at USA-MMA
is to bring back the feel,*
*and the excitement of a live event.*
*And we do them in rodeo arenas
and civic centers,*
*across South Louisiana.*
*And it's just me, my wife and the kids.*
- *[Gil's Wife] There's a definitely
a misperception about the sport*
*They laugh at the sport.
They can't wait to say,*
"Oh, really?
Well, that's human cock fighting."
I've heard that so many times
and it's aggravating because what?
*John McCain* said that 10-15 years ago,
'human cock fighting"
*And actually it probably was back then.*
*You know you can be in any weight class.*
*There was no rules at all*
But the way that the sports
developed since then.
You know it's very...
one of the safest sports around.
*Rodeo's, people die you know.
all the time, in rodeos*
*They die in NASCAR. All the time*
*But because this is a new sport
people don't know what it is*
*And they see so much blood,
they don't understand.*
Blood is superficial.
These guys has four ounce gloves on.
*They don't have 16 ounce gloves on.*
[Thud!]
*So there's no brain damage.*
*They're getting punched
with a 4 ounce glove.*
*If a guy in the ring is hurt,
the referee will stop the fight.*
*That won't happen in boxing.*
*His heirarchy has to be on the ground
he can even be hurt.*
*So as long as he can stand himself up*
*He could continue to fight.*
*And that doesn't happen in MMA either.*
*I knew when I started dating him
that he was a former boxer.*
*That he wrestled also, Pro,
which I thought was insane.*
[audience chanting] Let's go Gil! Uh! Uh!
[slamming]
Uh! Uh!
- [Gil's Wife]
It's in his blood. I mean my son's 5.
*And you know he's gonna fight one day.*
*You know, as safe as it is,
you still don't wanna see your son *
*even fall off his bike. You know. *
And he's gonna fight one day.
I will not be able to stop him.
It's in his blood.
My husband, when we argue
he goes to the gym and spars.
*And comes back
much better, much better.*
There's a lot of skill involved.
It's not just some, you know, bar fight.
If the guys calls all the time
"I wanna fight" , "I wanna fight"
"I wanna fight"
Well, if you're not trained.
You know we can't put you in there.
It's not safe.
- *[Gil] Yeah this is a rodeo arena
But you still not gonna fight on my show.*
A lot of these kids that call me up.
Wanting to fight,
think they first have the ability.
Then they think it's just, it's easy.
Let's go and do it
So, I as a 38,39 year old man
The first thing I do
is go to the gym and I'll spar 'em.
[swoosh] [ thud, thud]
Five guys walking off the street,
I'm looking for one thing,
all of them wanna be
world champion.
But the most important thing is,
Dedication
[thud, thud, thud]
[timer ringing]
-*[Tim] Don't commit to run.*
*Commit to the exchange.
You're committing to not getting hurt.*
- *[Albert Stainback] Actually, quite
afraid of being hit when I'm in the gym.*
*It sucks! You know you feel it.*
*But when I'm fighting, I just wanna
hit 'em and it just happens.*
*And I hit them. And they fall
unconscious and I feel good.*
*The energy in the cage makes
the whole thing feel spiritual for me.*
Like another world
It's almost like the universe
is this big machine.
And I am, you know, I'm operating it.
I don't believe in God.
I don't believe in destiny.
I don't believe in predetermination
or whatever anything like that.
But I will say I am dazzled
by the way I look at my life,
the way it's turned out and the way it's
just like interconnected with fighting
the way I feel it is.
It's the only thing that I really think
I'm good at, if anything.
You know if you could say
I'm good at anything, it would be that.
- *[Gil] Guy's got a lot of talent.*
*He's not a bad looking kid. *
*But I see potential in him
outside of fighting.*
*I think that if he really
put himself to anything.*
*He can do anything, he wanted to do.*
- [Albert] I kinda wanted to be my
only option.
Cause I love it that much.
Maybe that's a little fool hearted,
but I don't care.
- [Gil] Many mistakes
that a young fighter are making.
I guess, the most important one.
Is that they're forgetting.
That there's life after fighting.
Pursuing that MMA dream.
You know I can't fault anybody for that.
Because I pursued my own dream.
But I did work at the same time.
I went to college at the same time.
You don't understood
the sheer dynamics of it.
Most fighters 99% of fighters
end up broken and destitute.
That's just the truth of it.
They might make a little bit of money
here and there.
But most fighters, most people
climbing into the ring or the cage
don't make a penny.
*- [Tim] You try to help them
the best you can*
But they're not my children.
So what can I do?
- [Gil] Give them advice, that's about it.
Keep going with USA - MMA and [laughs]
Be the best company,
nobody's ever heard of.
[cheering and clapping]
*- [Gil] Hello and welcome to this
weeks edition*
*of the Combat Sports Report.
My name is Gil "The Thrill" Guillorey.*
What we have tonight is
"Natural Disaster III."
August 1st, Tonight. SugArena.
*It's gonna happen tonight guys.
We have 14 bouts.*
*A little too many fights*
*Our main event tonight is
"Joe Torres versus Dustin Poirier*
*Please, come out! Support these guys.*
*Support your local fighter.*
*We have, Mike Jackson
against Albert Stainback.*
*He's from Gladiator, Lafayette.*
- [Albert Stainback] I think a stare down.
Is something very important for a fight.
And yes I do practice in the mirror
I'll sit in the mirror in the bathroom
and just be like. [deep breathing]
If you're staring them down
And you see that certain look
I believed that you know,
you're already in their head.
And that, and that helps.
You know.
But then you get those people,
and this is when you know
It's gonna be a fight.
When they just look
right back at you dude...
And it's a..
I like those even better actually.
I like it when they grind, you know, right back.
When they are not scared.
When they do not back down. I love it!
- [Dustin Poirier] People feel the same
way when they get in the cage.
But other people in the outside
don't really notice it how,
you know, unless they do it,
how peaceful it really is inside there.
It's crazy, so pure.
- [Albert] When Dustin's in there
he looks like a serial killer.
You know and I feel like the same,
about myself.
Are we done yet?
*[announcer] Judges in the back park*
*will be meeting at 7 o'clock.
All fighters...*
- [Alvin Tapmam] *I wanna go over a few
things with you first, again,*
*I met most of you earlier, *
*my name is Alvin Tapmam,*
*I'm the commissioner,
For Athletics in State of Louisiana.*
The reason we're here primarily, the rules are followed
and safety, safety,safety is followed.
There's a lot of amateur fights
on this card tonight.
We'll stop the fight
before it gets to trouble
I'm just telling you right up, fellas.
I don't want anybody getting hurt.
We all know that when we come in
here that anybody.
Anybody. Anybody can get
severely injured in this sport.
It's happened before.
I'm sure it's gonna happen again.
You take that chance
when you go in that ring.
[♪ music ♪]
- *[Gil] We're not about sellin' fight,
We're selling entertainment.*
*And in that regard,
that is our bread circuit.*
[♪ music ♪]
- [Albert] I want people
to remember me.
I happen to think
that we came from monkeys,
so my little tribute to us,
getting in touch with our inner monkey
is I'll get out there
and I'll beat my chest twice.
You'll always see me do that
before a fight.
To me it's like that primal fight or flight thing.
*[crowd cheering and whistling]*
In a sense I do feel like a monkey
when I'm fighting.
It doesn't matter what his story is.
It doesn't matter what my story is.
It's a matter of
"Who's best fit to survive."
[Referee] Fight!
[crash]
[Albert Stainback] There is no feeling sorry
for your opponent.*
Because you know, it's do or die.
It's either you lose or he loses.
And I don't care what your story is,
man.
I gotta look out for me and mine.
[thud, thud,crash]
[crowd cheering]
With victory comes this elation
and that, you know, feels beautiful.
Like something I have
that no one can take from me.
You can earn, you can have a house,
you can have money.
You can have that
but you will lose that eventually.
And even if you don't,
what does it really mean?
*[crowd cheering]*
- [Dustin] Before a fight, I actually pray
that nobody gets hurt you know.
I don't wanna hurt him.
Or I don't wanna get hurt.
But I'm not scared to lose
or scared to get hurt in a fight.
*I expect to get hit you know.*
*I know, I'm not gonna go in there
and not get hit. It's a fight*
Just like a, just like
Going to work in an office
And not touchin' paper
or somethin' you know.
You gonna get hit it's part of the job.
- *[announcer] In the red pew.
Dustin Poirier!*
[crowd cheering]
- [Tim] Dustin is similar to me.
*He's a finisher.*
*Finishers are people
who don't fight to win rounds.*
*Or fight to win points,
without finishing the opponent.*
*No matter what the case. *
*Finish them, finish them,
finish them!*
*Finish the opponent.
Be fierce and be dominant.*
- [male voice screaming] Round 2!
*[crowd cheering]*
- *[announcer] Gladiators dominate, Dustin Porier!*
- *[Tim] A lot of times, you have guys
that work really really hard.*
*And make all the sacrifices.*
And then you have guys
that have really great talents.
Guys that do both. Become, you know,
some of the greatest fighters.
The world has ever seen.
And, you know,
it's exciting seeing a kid like Dustin,
*who may be one of those guys.*
*You know, as a coach,
as a trainer, as a fighter,*
*you may run into one or two
of those in your life.*
The biggest challenge now,
when it comes to a kid like Dustin,
is, you know finding somebody's
not gonna kill in a couple of minutes.
- [Gil] Will he make it to the UFC?
Will he be world champion?
Yeah... Potential.
But potential has a time frame.
*Potential has a time limit on it.*
*Twenty year old kid can have potential.*
*But if you still, if you're 38
and somebody says*
*"You still have potential,"*
it's time to move on, you know?
So, I give Tim's gym. Probably,
the nod as far as overall talent.
Cause the kids there can fight.
They can fight
*But that doesn't mean anything.
On the national scale*
♪ [music] ♪
*- [Jere Folley Chaisson] I have given my
boys, freedom to express themselves.*
*And to feel what they feel
and to do what they do.*
He loved to fight.
Not necessarily with, with
someone that he wasn't get along with.
He just wanted to have a fight
with somebody.
One day. When he must
have been just like 10 years old,
He got into trouble at school.
He had a note.
He came. He got off the school bus.
And he ran in the house.
He said "Here's the note.
I did something at school."
"Give me a whipping, if you're gonna
give me a whipping."
"Because I think. Somebody's
ready to fight me down the road."
They'd get these boxing matches
going on in the neighborhood.
And Dustin did that, you know?
And he, you know he was the best
out of all the little kids, the little guys that boxed.
Then there was this one guy that came
to meet him at his gradma's
and said, "Well you haven't boxed
me yet."
And Dustin, like, knocked out his teeth
and broke his jaw.
And he was like 5 years \older than Dustin.
And we have to go to court for that.
Yup!
He had a respect for the law but he didn't mind
having a run in with the law.
*That's when he started
skipping school.*
*And ended up in juvenile courts
and boot camp.*
*And juvenile jail and all of that stuff.*
[clicking]
-[Dustin] I definitely think fighting has
open the path to redemption for me.
I mean I've tried--I've been in boot camp.
And juvenile detention,
and programs and all these stuff.
They're suppose to help you.
And I mean, that didn't help, you know.
But when I found something
that I wanted.
And I really was gonna chase no matter
what road block was I front of me,
I would break it down and go get it.
This is a picture of me,
right when I started training.
I was probably about 200 pounds
in that picture.
Big transformation.
Look way different man.
People I did, haven't seen me
since I look like that.
The're like, don't even notice me
sometimes.
- He's finally found, what he's been
looking for all of this time.
*I know that he has been waiting
his whole life.*
*To climb up somethin'
and put his hands in the air.*
*Because he did it the best.*
- [Tim] As a kid in America.
We don't learn about honor.
And integrity and dignity
and compassion.
These lessons weren't taught
to me. I learned math.
*You know I learned science.
How to diagram a predicate*
*But I didn't know what honor was.*
*Martial arts is to develop the person.*
Your body, your mind and your spirit.
Everything is encompassed in that.
But an individual expression of that art,
is just that it's individualistic.
How I express my Jiu-Jitsu is different
from how Erin expresses his.
Or Heath expresses his.
And sometimes, some of that
is gonna have to do,
with your background a little bit.
You know, how athletic you are.
How athletic you're not.
Stop using muscles.
Don't have any muscles really to use.
Now, don't use any pressure
or any muscle.
I don't want you to do anything.
I just want you to grab his knee.
Now, unlock your hips, unlock.
There we go.. Good!
Now, this elbow needs to come
all the way down to the floor.
When you get tired.
Does strength work?
- *Don't have anymore*
Does technique work?
Only way that can happen is if you
technically beat the person.
Just like chess, same thing.
You know, all painters, you know,
they use, you know, the same paints
and the same canvasses,
and the same type of brushes.
But the paintings themselves.
Are all just so different.
They're so beautiful
and so glorious to watch.
When we fight that's where we make.
our masterpieces.
[♪music♪]
[metal banging]
- *[Gil] Friday the 13th
At the Lake Charles Civic Center*
*Where doing Boudoir number two. We're
bringing in a lot of the Lafayette Gladiator Guys.*
*We're also havin' Dustin Poirier. In our
main event and his fighting a guy*
*by the name of Ronnie Lis.*
*He's a brazilian Jiu-Jitsu black belt.*
*And he's gonna be
a serious threat to Dustin.*
*And we've got Paul Swallow.*
*Taken on Albert Stainback
in his pro debut.*
[plates clanging]
[Dustin] Right now.
I'm just bussing tables and training.
And I like to train more,
I'd like to fight more.
I wanna step up my career path.
Again not only as a fighter
But to feel like I'm doing something.
Like becoming an adult I guess.
Fighting for my job
[men talking]
- [Albert] This first pro fight.
It's actually gonna pay my rent.
We're actually so behind on rent.
It's not even funny.
And I really hope I'll win this fight.
We used to not be behind on rent.
My girlfriend is used to be a stripper.
And then like, like, you know,
we'd eat sushi everyday.
And we'd freaking you know,
go out of town and have fun.
You know, I kinda feel half of it is my fault--
[train blowing it's horn]
- *[Tim] I have all kinds of guys
come in here.*
Under the impression they're
gonna be fighters.
And I think most guys do not realize,
that this is a 40 hour week job.
This is a grind, you know?
What makes great fighters
and what makes great champions
Is the endurance to deal with the grind.
*You know its 5, 6 days a week of grinding. *
*2 or 3 hard practices per day out.*
♪ [music] ♪
- [Albert] Training with Tim has just--
it's helped my confidence
a lot actually,
because he's the only guy
I know who'll talk to me
like I talk to myself in my head.
And I know he's really just trying to push
and see the best "me" I can be.
♪ [music] ♪
*- [Tim] At the end of the day.
MMA is an individual sport.*
*But it is also a team sport.*
* I can't train myself alone.*
*The bags do not hit back.*
[grunting]
[male voice] fuck!
- [Corey Judice] Tim will definitely let you know.
If you're not showing up.
- *[Albert] * How he feels about it.
[punching]
[male voice] move, move, move.
step out of there.
$$ Makes you feel better huh?
$$ come on..
[man yelling] Hah!
[timer ringing]
- *[Tim] The expectations of our gym
are not you have to win every fight.*
*You don't have to win every fight*
*But you do have to train for every fight.*
- [Tim] Pier, if you say something
like that again.
You're out of the gym forever.
Do you understand?
If you think I'm fucking here.
To waste my fucking time on you.
You've lost your mind.
You don't do shit for me
when I spar with you.
You ever say that to me again.
You're out of the gym forever.
*You hear me?*
- *[Pierre] Yes boss!*
*[Tim] You need to have some respect.*
*You need to understand, that while
you have been doing.*
*Whatever it was you needed
to be doing in your time.*
*We've been here working.*
*So don't be mad at me,
or frustrated with me.*
*Because you're getting destroyed.*
*You'll found other things to do with
your time than come to practice.*
You know Corey's fight in Baton Rouge,
he took a horrendous beating.
You know he got beat on
bad, you know.
- *[announcer] Making his way
Into the red corner. Corey Judice*
- [Tim] When we go out there
and the music's over.
*And you get in there
and the door closes.*
I'm not goin' in there with you.
*I can't save you.
You have to save yourself.*
*Because the chances of you
getting hurt in a fight*
before the fight ends are 100% in your career.
It is not acceptable to try to survive.
You must be fighting to win.
You must be fighting to finish.
'Cause once you give up,
the next 5 or 6 punches
are gonna put you in the hospital.
You can never give up.
You must fight until you can't
physically fight anymore.
Or until you win.
-*[announcer] In the red corner..
Corey Judice*
[Crowd cheering]
[Tim] I'm glad he won the fight.
And you know of course...
But I'm more proud that
he made it through there.
You know... And he got beat
up a little bit.
And he got black eye and stuff.
But you know, he was in some
dangerous position a couple times.
And because of the fact that we live
in dangerous position at the gym.
You know he was able
to defend himself.
And he was able to get out.
And he was able to not sustain
the type of damage.
That could have render him
hurt really bad.
You know, and it's my responsibility
to know they're ready to deal
with what happen.
So, I just take it seriously and--
but, I ain't sparred with the guy in 2 weeks.
He's got fight this week.
You know sometimes.
I'm too rough maybe...
And sometimes I go,
you know, maybe over the line.
But you know what.
They don't get hurt.
And they beat the crap
out of people.
[gong clanging]
- [Albert ] My dad used to beat
my mom. Senseless.
And and I always put that in my head
whenever I think about certain things.
You know, when I go to my
angry place. I guess.
He had my mom by the throat.
He picked her up.
And blood was running down
his arm out of her mouth.
'Cause he was like digging
into her mouth with his thumbs.
And shit like that.
And then, [clears throat] ,
my dad shot himself when I was 9.
And my mom went off
on a big alcoholic binge.
So there was a lot of stuff that happened,
I guess, you could say that
made me kinda wanna fight.
I honestly attribute me wanting to fight,
if I have to give some kind of
Freudian guess at it,
It is to--I wanted to be a defender.
♪ [music] ♪
I believe life is all about balance.
And violence is part of that balance.
[birds chirping]
- [Dustin] When somebody ask me.
What you do for a living?
I don't say, *I'm a professional fighter.*
I say,"I work in Cane and Co.
I drive a delivery truck."
You know, I can't lie to somebody
and say "I'm a professional fighter."
I might make money doing it
but is that my profession?
Is that what I do
to provide for me and my wife?
I'm trying to make it that.
- [Jere Folley Chaisou]
Back then if you wrote left,
they try to make you right with it.
- [Dustin Forrier] Do I always right left?
- [Jere Folley Chaisou] Yeah.
- [Dustin Forrier] Really?
Yup.
[Dustin Forrier] No way
I'm telling you
He's accomplished so much.
He went from this alcoholic kid to,
you know, professional fighter.
He owns his own home, he
works just minimally,
Just a few hours.
Just to keep his benefits.
He's my hero and he's gonna do it.
I know that he is..
He's gonna be amazing.
He's gonna be a household name.
♪ [music] ♪
- [Gil] If you can't sell tickets
I can't use you.
*[man on phone] Go down baby,
go down.*
Because I can't make money.
If I gotta pay a fighter $15000,
a $1000 to show up.
Another $1000 to win. But he can't
sell worth $4000 worth of tickets.
*[man on phone] You should have
- Will you pay somebody that hard. *
Most of the time if they're really good.
They won't show.
You know they just. They didn't know
how to bring the crawl.
[man on phone] I - I know
The bite of my own ass
part of it. Is that.
I have to hyped that fighter
up so much.
That they're friends and families
start to make them believe it.
They start believing it.
They come to me,
demanding more money.
Because they honestly believe
that their worth it.
Because everyone else tells them
that they're the 2nd coming.
And little do they know.
You're not the 2nd coming.
You're exactly what I made you to be.
I've promoted you this way.
I've made you this way.
I can take Gary Coleman and turn
and take Gary Coleman.
And promote him properly.
And everybody will come to see
Gary Coleman fight.
So you're no more special than he is.
- *And you know what I'd make a killing*
*[man on phone] Cause he is -
Looks phenomenal.*
- [Albert ] I'm the main event?
- *[Gil] Not, you're semi.*
- [Albert] Oh semi, that's cool,
open it up for Dustin always love it.
- *[Gil] Need to... yeah...
Need to provide...*
- *[male voice] Semi is what you are.*
- Semi pro.
- [male voice] Yup.
- [Gil] Hep. B and C results.
- [male voice] ♪ Love me sexy ♪
- [Gil] And HIV result no more than 6 month old.
- [Albert] I'd just ask you bout that.
I got some results but the 13th,
they will be officially 3 days overdue.
Do you want me to go ahead and...?
- [Gil] No, you have to.
Yeah, they're over 6 months.
- [Albert] I got you homes.
You put "back" on there didn't you?
- [Gil] "Stain-back."
- [Albert] There we go.
- [Gil] And we'll make a copy of this
if there's a machine in here.
But I don't think there is
- [Albert] I'm sure if I'm gonna weigh in,
I weigh in at 155 pounds.
Got you, no problem.
[paper flipping] [pen screeching]
♪ [music] ♪
- [Dustin] I'm ready to do it.
I'm ready to fight.
I'll fight tonight if I could.
If I have to fight tonight,
I'd be ready to go.
Of course, after I drink a little bit
and not be so dizzy.
I'm mentally ready to fight.
Physically, hurting.
But this is part of it.
The fight already started for me.
This is the fight right now.
It's part of the fight
Tomorrow about 1 o'clock,12 o'clock.
I'll be done. I'll be about 155.
Just gotta keep sweating.
♪ [music] ♪
[mans voice] stop! stop!
[people talking]
-* [Gil's wife] Let's see,
say's the woman on the telephone *
wanted to know exactly what this,
Louisiana versus Florida event was all about.
Telling her it was mixed martial arts
Didn't seem to answer that question.
It's cage fighting,
Gillory said it wasn't to say the least
what she wanted to hear.
She said, "That's disgusting.
I wanna do everything in my power
"To make sure this never
comes back here."
I don't know if that's good
or bad but it starts off with that.
- *[Gil] It's good, all press is good.*
*All right, Dustin Poirier, main event
155 pounds Gladiator Academy.*
- *[male voice] Hey, Gil. Grey wants to
know where to get his ticket from?*
* [Gil] One fifty-four point oh.*
Who?
- *[male voice] Grey.*
- [Gil] Who's Grey?
No,no. Civic center.
*Ronnie, are you ready, bro?*
- [Gil] One fifty three. Main event.
Guys we got a fight.
- * [male voice] Yeah.*
-* [Gil] Semi main event, 155 pounds*
- [Albert ] We're the semi!
We're like the opening band.
-*[male voice] Yeah*
[phone ringing]
- *[Gil] . Who's that?*
- *[male voice] You're old man.*
- *[Gil] Answer it.*
[men talking]
- [Gil] One fifty four point two.
Okay, yeah, tell them thanks.
- *One fifty-two point eight.*
Good job boys.
[chewing]
- That's not monkey.
[slurping]
Oh God.
♪ [music] ♪
- [foreign language]
I'm a victor in 1 minute.
Be careful my opponent
Dustin is gonna be in
for a tough fight.
They wanted a tough opponent,
I got them a tough opponents
So we're gonna see exactly
what happens with them tomorrow.
- [Albert] For my first pro fight. I'll be
making you know 500 show and five to win.
This is real now. This isn't
some amateur fight. You know...
From every move I make from now on.
Will determine if I can eat.
I know I have. You know,
moments of worry. But...
When you step into that cage,
you prove it to yourself.
And I've proven it to myself 17 times.
That I've got what it takes to do this.
And I'm gonna do it.
- This is a mixed crowd.
We're gonna have kids
We're gonna have ladies
We're gonna have
lots of people here.
It's not gonna be in a bar room situation.
So keep you language down. I don't
wanna hear any 4 letter words. Okay?
In an event you have to go
to the hospital.
Let the doctor determine if you're
gonna go to the hospital or not.
Okay?
You discuss it with the doctor.If you
feel bad, if you got a major injury.
You feel like you got something
seriously wrong with you.
Let the doctor discuss that with the
EMT's and the ambulance people.
And coordinate.
Don't just in an ambulance and
say, "Take me to the hospital."
[beep, beep, beep]
- [Tim] There's an arrogance in Brazil,
in a lot of levels. And--
When it comes to Jiu-Jitsu. I've been
there a few times to train. And--
You know sometimes those guys
since you know, Jiu-Jitsu kinda--
really kinda started it all on a lot of levels.
They believe when they come over here,
we're just not necessarily ready for them.
And, you know, they're just gonna
really show us what a real fighter is about.
And, you know that might have been the case
many years ago,
but it's not the case anymore, you know...
Dustin's a young kid in
South Louisiana.
But he's got 2 black belts
at his disposal.
That he trains in regularly and coming to America
and fighting a guy who's never seen Jiu-Jitsu,
It's not a real, not real scenario anymore.
And the fact the guys thinks that,
indicates to me that,
Maybe he's not necessarily
been around fighting for that--
that long around here.
And I think that Dustin's opponent may
need to learn that the hard way tonight.
- [Dustin] I just want to crack him on his chin.
[crowd cheering]
- [Gil] Jesus Christ!
What have we got ourselves into?
[male voice] I know, I gotta have music go.
[crowd cheering]
[yelling]
♪ [music] ♪
[crowd clapping]
- What's on my mind?
What's on my mind is I'm here to win.
You're in the way of my destiny.
Get out of my way.
I'm the better fighter. I'm here to win
[Gil] Use them hands, Albert
- [Tim] When Albert was kid I sure he
never saw the lines in his color book.
His fighting is not neat, it's not pretty
but he defintely colors the whole page.
Just like that kid you know.
He fights hard, he never quits.
He fights to finish you.
No matter what he fights to finish.
[crowd cheering]
- [Albert] When the fears of losing
or the fears of not being able to
pursue my career
or getting hurt start going to my head,
there's a voice in my head that says,
you know, "What are you doing?
You could get hurt for life,
you could fail."
You know, when that fear and doubt
comes up, even that voice comes out.
It's almost like a person.
I beat the fuck out of it.
You know, I'd kick it down the stairs.
You know, I chain it to the basement.
Kick it a few more times for
good measure.
Then I head back upstairs
and I lock that door.
Because I will not have that fear
stop me from doing what I wanna do.
[crowd cheering]
*[announcer] Stop picking accidents 350.
One of the first three rounds*
*In the blue corner,
representing Gladiators academy,*
*Albert Stainback!*
[crowd mixed cheering and booing]
- Yeah, I'd love a rematch.
I mean, I spent 4 and half minutes
on top of the guy. Pounded him out,
trying to choke him.
Next time I'd make sure I'd do that
for 15 minutes not just four and half.
You know, but what you gonna do?
You don't complain about it.
You go back to the gym
and start training.
- [announcer] Alright, ladies and
gentlemen.
This your tenth and final bout--
is the main event!
- [Dustin] It's just kinda crazy.
I'm really nervous before.
Cause I've played the
fight over my head.
Like this guy I'm about to fight.
Men, I've fought him a million times
already In my head.
Just in this last month. You know?
I've beat him a million times.
Already in my head.
[thud, thud, thud]
When it's time to walk out there
to the cage.
It's just the time to actually do it.
I kinda feel full of joy.
Man, when I'm walking to the cage.
I'm happy.
[Dustin] HAH!
- [announcer] Dustin Poirier.
Three five minute rounds.
One fifty five pound weight division
♪ [music] ♪
[referee] Don't wanna fight.
[crowd cheering]
-*[male voice] Aint got no stand up. *
[thud, thud, thud]
-*[Gil] Get him Dustin. Beautiful.*
[slam]
Uhmp! Uhmp!
*[crowd screaming]*
[mans voice] Elbows hold them,
elbow relax.
[floor banging]
[crowd cheering]
[crowd yelling]
[man yelling] Get back up!
[slam, slam, slam]
[Tim] Be more respectful next time
- [Dustin] Hey K. Your hand pop.
And pop, pop, pop!
-* [referee] You're on the wrong side.*
- *[announcer]
Fighters to the center of the ring. *
*We go to the official score card.*
*You're winner after 354 seconds
of the first round by way of tap out,*
*In the red corner Dustin Poirier!*
*[man talking] Dude, Jiu-jitsu
was good.*
- [Dustin] Oh yeah, it was. I was
ice skating through them heel hooks.
He had it for a second
a heel hook but I turned it over
and he went into a knee bar.
- *[Tim] So how long did that take,
Dustin?*
-Fifty seven seconds. What he said is,
he's gonna beat me in a minute.
So you gotta watch out
what you say sometimes.
You gotta eat your words you know.
- At his own game baby.
Oh my God! Hey!
[Crowd laughing]
- History is written by the
victor, ultimately--
I mean, because the losers dead.
He wants a rematch.
So he wants me at my best.
So I'll give him "Me" at my best.
I've noticed that when I'm not training.
And I'm not on the path
to being a great fighter,
like I want to be,
like I tell everybody I want to be,
like I tell myself I want to be,
it seems that's when
the bad shit in my life happens.
That seems like that's when all--
everything starts going to shit.
And when I'm doing what
I'm suppose to be doing
to be a great fighter.
Nothing can go wrong in my life.
♪ [drum beats] ♪
- [Gil] Hey guys! How ya all doin?
- Hey, we're doing a show at
the Cajundome
for caged fighting on March 6.
I don't know if you're all into it but
if you all are, please come by
and come by, check it out, okay?
All right you all.
Remember how the circus would
come to town when you're a kid?
They'd unload the animals at the train
station and parade them through town.
They'd use the elephants as
billboards.
They'd have the clowns and midgets
walking behind creating excitement.
Well, I do the same thing,
only my car is my elephant
and postcards are my midgets.
[crowd screaming]
Throw me something!
[whistle blowing]
♪ [band music] ♪
[thump, thump, thump]
[thud, thud, thud]
[muttering]
I'm fighting Derrick Krantz..
He's a pretty young, a year or two older than me.
I think he might be 22 years old
He's got a lot of fights.
That doesn't intimidate me, you know?
I know what my hands can do too.
I'm gonna meet him in the middle
of the cage and we're gonna fight.
When you have two guys like that meet
up in the cage in front of audience.
Man, you have no choice
but to have a great fight.
And you know two guys who
go at each other like that
neither of us is gonna back down.
And that's for sure you're gonna see
fireworks you know.
It's gonna be great fight to watch.
- [Albert] As of late, you know
I've been showing up at the gym
maybe three times a week and hitting two
or three classes or one, you know.
So it's not been very well, like, I said,
a lot of people go to the gym
and they train to get rid of stress.
And, I don't know. I'm just different.
You know when something is on my
mind it's hard for me to train.
So that's been my problem lately. Just
you know, lot of personal problems.
Relationship wise. You know,
things aren't working out.
And like I said that's weight on me
that I've been carrying into the gym.
I think the big problem was that
I felt out of control with my last,
you know, the situation with Chelsea,
with my ex-girlfriend and everything.
I felt very out of control and it just--
it bothered me. It threw me off.
But now, I'm in one of those situations
where everything's up to me,
you know, if I don't have a place to live,
that's on me.
If I don't win fights or I don't, you know
I don't perform well, that's all on me.
You know, I don't have anything in my way
that anyone else doesn't.
You know what I'm saying?
So let's see what happens.
[Door closing]
♪ [music] ♪
- *[Dustin] When you devout yourself
to something like I do fighting,*
it just changes. It drowns out
all the other stuff going on.
It kinda helps me focus on one thing,
it's almost like natural now
to do the right things.
I'm really in touch with my body.
I think my body knows when its time
to prepare for a fight.
And get it sharp and get it crisp
and get it read to go to the battle.
When it's time to fight my weapons
are ready.
- *[Tim] Albert and I missing his practice
is all so crazy. *
He maybe came one time in three weeks
and so, he call me today
and says he's not ready to fight,
which he's not but I told him
he doesn't have the ability to pull out
right now because it's up to Gil.
You already gave you word,
it's two weeks outs.
You have another professional
training to fight you.
This isn't an amateur fight, you know?
There's another guy who's got
money on the line
and bills on the line,
you just can't pull out on that guy
because you had too much drama.
[train honking]
- Okay so he told you
he still doesn't know
if he wants to fight or not?
- He doesn't want to or does he?
- Here's the thing,
just don't even talk to him no more.
- He talked to me, yeah.
- If you can find him,
find Swallow an opponent,
- I can.
- then that guy needs
to fight Paul.
- Okay that's none on--
- If you can't fight Paul Swallow
an opponent,
I'll make Albert fight, cause its--
I'm not gonna let Paul Swallow
lose the fight.
- Right.
- You know that, that has to be,
you know, rewarded or penalized
on some level from a team
perspective, you know?
[train honking]
- *[Gil] We all need to be on the
same page, okay?*
- Okay.
- Tim says that you're not fighting.
You're saying, you don't know
if you're fighting.
I'm saying you better off not fighting,
I'm also saying that if you're
gonna fight.
I understand, however,
I don't recommend it
unless absolutely need
the money, okay?
Tim asked me not to talk to you
about it just, you know...
But I just wanted you and I to look at
each other and be on the same page now.
I don't really think that you're mind is into it.
I don't know if you feel
like you're letting me down
because you're really not.
So I need you to hear you say it,
"I'm not fighting."
- That's really hard.
- But you gotta say it because
I don't want there be any--just tell me
you're not fighting and then we'll get over it.
See what I'm saying?
- Uh-huh. Give me--give me a day.
Can I have a day?
Or can I have this evening,
the rest of this evening?
- Yeah, you can have the rest
of this evening.
And there's no sweat off on
nobody's back. Start fresh.
- *[Tim] We're gonna do little gloves
today and Wednesday, okay?*
Just so we kinda take some
of the heat off you guys
not beating each other up so bad, you know?
[timer rings]
[thud, thud, thud]
-*[male voice] Just grab one, June.
Just grab one of his legs. Suck it up.**
Little lighter Fakroe.
You gotta fight in two weeks.
Lighter. Slow down.
Oh, Fakroe! Slow down!
Go!
Shit! Control yourself.
Fucking think this is?
[thud, thud, thud]
[alarm beeps]
Great job! good work. We're there!
Just stick around.
Alby go with D. Let's go repair,
you got 30 seconds.
[thud, thud, thud]
Get down!
-*[Tim] Bring him down.*
[heavy breathing]
[thud]
-*[male] You gotta have to pay for it
one way or another, might as well do it now.*
-*[male] Take it like a man, come on!*
-*[male] Keep your hands up, Albert.
Come back to your face. *
[heavy breathing]
[beep]
♪ [music] ♪
- I'm thankful you know,
for the ass beating I just received.
You know these guys are just trying
to keep real with me.
They're just trying to show like,
"*Hey, you need to be in the gym."*
You know after two rounds of sitting
there and dying when--
You know, like Tim said, two months ago
I was killing almost everybody,
you know.
So, this isn't the last opportunity I'll have.
And I--I really need to be thankful for that.
It's just, it sucks knowing
that I let something like this go by.
You know, it might be small, might be big,
but it was there.
And I'm not one to--to like it
when I screw up.
- *[Tim] In fighting, most of the time,
you're, you're own worst enemy.*
*You know unfortunately,
Albert beat himself.*
♪ [music] ♪
*You know fighting is a microcosm for life.*
*The credit belongs to the person that's
out there.*
*And the person that's putting
themselves on the line*
*to do something, to be something. *
*To push their level and push who
they are as a person*
* to greater and greater heights.*
[tap, tap, tap]
- *[Tim] For Dustin Poirier to lose,*
*It's gonna take someone to beat him
but Dustin is not gonna beat himself.*
[thump]
[thud, thud, thud]
-*[male] Come on reach it*
- *[male voice] As you jab,
that's a measuring stick.*
-*[Dustin] Reach you literally across--*
-*[male voice] Well, yeah, but your jab
is like a measuring stick.*
*That's what put you in position.
That's where I'm gonna be, right there.*
-*[male voice] Everyone can walk,
but then to be a run way model,*
*you have to learn how to walk.*
*He knows how to fight. *
*But he just possess an unbelievable
amount of heart and determination.*
*And if you can give a fighter a
heart and determination, *
*the sky's absolutely the limit. *
*'Cause this ultimately--*
*the MMA and the boxing's gonna end
one day and they didn't learn anything*
* while they were boxing,
then this was all done in vain.*
[thud, thud, thud]
-What make you hit those
angles, you know?
- *[Gil] You're looking at that hook
before you throw it.*
*I saw you doing it. You were doing
this, *bam, bam*. *
*And you look at that hook before
you threw it.*
- 'Cause I'm trying to keep
my hook like--
even with my head I'm trying not to
arm it like I used to.
I used to throw hooks from here.
-That's good. That's your hook.
- I'm thinking about it a little bit
too much.
- You look good, you look good.
It's a good thing. A good thing that
happen would be for the promotion
would be, if you'd lost.
-*[Gil] 'Cause if you lost then I could sell
a rematch. *
If you win I can't sell a rematch.
You know?
So, you want to make some real money.
You'd get ready to lose.
- Shit!
Everybody got their dreams.
No rematching buddy.
♪ [music] ♪
- *[Gil] The family element is essential
to us because USA-MMA is my family.*
*Me, my wife, my children
and we all promote this event.*
*But when we're all together out there
trying to enjoy a good day together.*
*And we're promoting the event *
*at the same time and people
see me and and my wife,*
*my son, my daughter who is
3 years old passing, off flyers,*
*it's not a gimmick, but it helps. *
*It helps people see that, *"Man!
this is alright,"* you know?*
*"It could be okay.
Lets go, lets give it a shot."*
[drum beating]
- That's a big face.
-You see the face over there?
Say, "Throw me something, mister"
-*[girl] Throw me something, mister.*
That's a good stuff, the coins. Look.
You got coins? Look, grab your coins.
Come on ya'all
-* [Gil] How long before we have to--*
- Oh you got, you got a couple
of minutes.
- I gotta wake my wife up,
take the kids to school.
- We'll talk the aspect--
- Hey!
-*[wife] Hi!*
- Okay, just making sure,
I'm about to go on camera--
- Tell us how good we look,
tell us if we look good.
- Bob said to tell him if he looks good.
Bye!
Alright bye!
- Alright, that was a look
at Fitness first,
23 minutes after 6 o'clock,
Wednesday morning
on Fox 2.
Gill Guillory with USA-MMA.
We are taking it up a notch this
coming Saturday at the Cajundome.
- That's right
- Who are we gonna see in action?
- Well, we're gonna see in the main event,
Derrick Krantz from Texas versus
Dustin Poirier out of St. Martinville.
That's for our USA-MMA championship.
Paul Swallow from Lake Charles
will be in, he'll be fighting also.
We have a ton of Gladiator
guys that'll be fighting in the show.
Cajun karate guys fighting
on the show.
We have people from
Oklahoma,Dallas.
-* [Bob] All right, also, I'm gonna be the
ring announcer.*
So mark that done, you know what date.
And of course, the all important,
there's gonna be ring girls.
- We got ring girls but we have a
special announcement today.
Our special guest ring girl will
be Ms. Julie Darcy.
- [Bob] No. You don't wanna do that.
- *[Gil] I'm still nervous,
I mean, you know,*
A show that cost you a $55,000,
if I lose $55,000 I gotta go to work,
you know, I mean...
I'm not rich. I mean I work but
I work for myself.
- *[Bob] Fifty-five thousand!*
- That's what it cost to put
on a show, you know.
- [Bob] People have come to realize now
that there's so much...
- [Gil] Right
- You get what you paid for.
-[Tim] It's tough to make a living
fighting. It's really tough.
Your entire career is controlled with
your hands.
*You build your own destiny,*
*brick by brick, with you own
hands. Fight by fight.*
I don't see martial arts
as a career path. I see it as a lifestyle.
*I enjoy the fear, I enjoy the
nervousness, I enjoy that.*
That's why I do this
The point of the entire thing
is to build yourself into a better person.
Not to make yourself a richer person.
- [Dustin] I mean, I feel a lot of pressure
with this fight.
Because I just signed that contract
with Dinero Sports Marketing.
What is he gonna think if I'd
lose this fight?
That's putting pressure on me thinking
about that. That's why, if I lose this fight,
is my manager gonna say,
"Well, I think he's even ready to fight
even tougher guys now."
When it come down to it.
All I can do is fight
[thud, thud, thud]
- [male] Give me some more,
Give me some more
- [Dustin] It's not hard to harm
another person.
To knock another person out.
I mean this is a simple task that has
to be done in the cage.
And just as simple as I can do it to you,
you can do it to me.
- This guys coming to,
basically, in Dustin's living room
at his home and trying to defeat him.
This is Dustin's house!
This is Lafayette, Louisiana.
And it's his home where
he was born and raised.
This guy can't come to Lafayette
and win this fight. It's impossible!
-[Dustin] Anything can happen
in fighting.
All it takes is one mistake, one punch.
Me knowing that. Makes me a little
bit prepared for a good fight I think.
[birds chirping]
*I want this fight more than anything
and I think about it 24 hours a day*
Derrick's fighting the best Dustin Poirier
anybody has ever fought
One sixty one on the money.
Six more pounds.
*Fourteen pounds already*
Today's Thursday, four days, 14 pounds.
You know I'm eating three times a day now.
While I'm cutting weight,
only six to eight ounce piece of fish.
But still you know, put the little bit of sides
but still that's way better, you know,
keep my body from breaking itself down.
Oh, man! Raw organic coconut butter.
It's so horrible
I'm suppose to be takin these because
I'm not eating any carbohydrates really.
Beside the Quiona, but that's not too many.
And your body needs energy
so it doesn't break down the muscles.
[crackling]
When I cut weight,
I'd like to watch the food network.
Pretending I'm swimming in a pool
of icing like that.
-*[mans voice] What else sounds good?*
How much time you got?
I love ice cream. Like the cookies.
Like ice cream sandwiches. What!
The make peanut butter one inside
Wal-mart, between two chocolate things
The peanu--
the ice cream is peanut butter flavored.
I'd eat a whole box of 'em after I fight.
[men chattering]
- Hello, this is Gil.
We have a ton of tickets, man.
Grab about 50 of your friends
and come on down
If we don't sell tickets.
This house's is on the line.
*For us to be profitable,
we have to do everything.*
*We have to do the lighting,
ticket taking, ticket selling.*
*We have to do everything
or we loose everything.*
- Whatever I'm wearing to fight.
I have to put it inside a target bag.
Has to be target bag.
I have to buy juicy fruity bubble gum
and chew it the whole day before I fight.
I'd be fighting Derrick Krantz, my breath
would be smelling like bubble gum
Mango flavored Walgreen's Pedialyte
every time.
Not Pedialyte brand, Walgreen's brand.
It taste like victory.
For the weigh-ins, I always have
to buy new boxers
I think I'm on a roll with weighing in
with a gray one's on.
So I think I'd probably wear these
cause these are kinda cool
They have a black top and they're gray,
so it's pretty cool.
I think I'll weigh-in with these on most likely.
Unless somethin' changes in my mind,
I'd have to wear these.
We'll see. Otherwise I'm normal.
[tv playing]
- [Jere Folley Chaissou] It's a hard week
for all of us,
It's like, a year ago,
yesterday, my mom died.
And I know that, that's been heavy on him
very heavy. Very heavy.
Because she and I raised him
by the skin of our teeth.
When he points up to heaven after he
wins, he's pointing up to his grandma.
She's got the best seat in the house
♪ [music] ♪
- [Gil] Come a long way since the rodea
arena's but,
we may go back to the rodeo arena.
The profit margin is so high
on the rodeo arena, that--
that's what justifies going there
in the first place.
So, if we get 5,000 people tomorrow night,
We'll be back. It just depends man,
I'm scared.
Scared to death.
It's a big step you know.
-*[announcer] One fifty-five is the weight class.
Derrick Krantz willl be up first.*
*One fifty-five point four.*
*Dustin Poirier, one fifty-five point four.*
[audience clapping]
*One, two, three, four.
One, two, three, four.*
*One, two, one, two, one, two.*
*Let's - we may have to make some
minor adjustments once again.*
-*[male] When was the last time
you passed out?*
When was the last time you fought?
- This is your first fight?
Never fought anywhere in Texas at all?
-* [Gil] This is my man.*
*Derrick D-Rock Krantz, here for the
USA-MMA 155 pound title.*
Mr. Krantz, What is your projection
for the main event this evening?
- I'll take a first round knock out any day.
- And become the USA-MMA
155 pound champion
and hopefully move on to bigger
and better things
Here and the near future.
Derrick D. Krantz and Gil "The Thrill"
Guillory checking out.
- We want everyone here
from Lafayette Louisiana.
It's the USA-MMA champion on the line.
Derrick Krantz will be going up against
Dustin Poirier, Poirier
♪ [music] ♪
- We welcome you here to
Cajun country.
[foreign language]
[crowd cheering]
- I'm proud of you,
good work. Thank you, man.
- Thank you, thank you very much.
I can't breathe but it's all good.
Hey Bau. Hey Bau, are you okay?
- *[Bau] What? Just a broken nose.*
- [Gil] Bau's got a broken nose and
swellling.
He got into war with a 260 pound
guy and -- I mean...
He says his head hurt and they're
trying to take him away in
an ambulance for a broken nose.
I'm like, "Dude, you're not going away
in an ambulance.
Have your momma drive you to the
hospital," you know.
It's like crazy. He'll be fine,
it's just they'r scared you know.
They don't understand. They're scared.
He's never been beat like that.
He's a fighter though.
He's fuckin' as tough as nails
and he did what he could.
Baby girl, love of my life.
Come with daddy.
wanna come with daddy. I love you,
wanna come work with me?
Let's go work
[hard breathing]
- Dustin Poirier will hit Derrick
Krantz so hard,
the alarm in the nearby bank
will go off.
- *[Dustin] What you think?, It's perfect.*
- [Tim] You're gonna need it.
[announcer calling]
- [Dustin] It's about to go down.
- [Tim] I know.
- *[Gil] Many fans and family and friends
do not understand the reality of fighting.*
- [announcer] Derrick D-rock.
*They immediately pawn off
Dustin's opponent.*
*As if he's some person
on a prison release program,*
*just coming here to get beat up.*
*And get some cigarettes
or something. *
*This is another dangerous
trained professional fighter,*
*who has finished a lot of individuals. *
*And he's coming here
to destroy Dustin.*
♪ [music] ♪
[crowd yelling and cheering]
- *[male] Let's work baby, hand's up
chin down.*
[slamming on the floor]
[crowd cheering]
*[male] Use a clock face,
use a clock face.*
*[man] Keep working it, keep working it*
-* [male] Lock it up, lock it up, grab
your shit, keep the triangle.*
- *[male] Lock your right foot down.
Lock your triangle and pull his hand.*
*[male] Grab the wrist. One more.*
- *[male] You your shit Dustin!*
- *[male] Close your guard, tighten it up.*
- $$[Derrick] You are doing good.
- $$*[Dustin] Thank you.*
-* [male] Keep working, control the wrist.*
*Control the wrist,control the wrist*
- *[male] Off the bottom Dustin push your hips.*
[horn blowing]
- Stuck up, don't make
me snap. You get out there and fight!
Put your chin on and go to work
on this boy.
This boy does not want
to be in the ring with you.
You hear what I'm telling you.
You go to work!
- [Tim] He's taking you down
for a reason.
You put it in your mind you gonna
knock this mother fucker out.
You put your chin on, you put your
hands up. You start throwing shots!
Make him punish this thing!
- *[male] Hand's up, chin down, bite down,
bite them mouth piece, go to work.*
-*[male] Alright take him down.*
- [Tim] It just sometimes it feels like
my hearts gonna come out of my chest
you know.
♪ [music] ♪
[crowd cheering]
[Tim] Work it now, work it, work it.
♪ [music] ♪
- [Tim] Proud of you.
You beat that thing.
You deserve it.
- [Tim] I know I don't say it,
but I love these guys.
*[announcer] How about a round
of applause for both fighters.*
Wow!
[crowd cheering]
*Fighters to the center of the ring. *
*Dustin Poirier!*
[crowd cheering]
♪ [music] ♪
- [Dustin] People will say
this is a crazy dream
or like a fantasy dream
that I'm chasing.
And I won't be able to do it,
you know, what's their dream?
What are they gonna do
with their life?
- *[Gil] I wish that when I was his age*.
* I had the ability to separate those things*
*and get those bad things out of my life. *
*I didn't care man. I did--I partied and
tried to burn the candle at both ends. *
He's not doing that.
When I look at Dustin, I look at
- and of course dangerous
word again "potential".
Potential to actually be something
in this sport.
Twenty one with his mind on the game.
- *[Dustin] "Fortune favors are bold,"
you know, Virgil said that.*
- So a kid that's 21 years old with
15 fights and one loss.
Would for sure need to step out a little bit
and go fight
in the major league organization
[crowd roaring]
- [male] Three combo, hus, hus, hus!
Good. One combo.
- [Dustin] Hus, hus, hus. hus!
♪ [music] ♪ [
- [Dustin] It's for me and my wife
and family.
- [Gil] Somebody's dreams
gonna get crushed tonight.
And we're fairly certain
it's gonna be Derek Gauthier's dream.
*We're not here to crush Derrick
or hurt Derrick*
*but we are here to put a yield sign
in his dreams.*
-*[Tim] Just like we always say*.
*You could walk to the ring
with a 100 chicks*
and have any nickname you want
*But once the door closes down.
Ain't nobody coming to save you.*
*Nobody saves you. *
You got stitches, stitches?
you get stitches? No? Let me see.
-* [Gil] It's important for a fighter
mentally and spiritually ,*
to be able to walk into an
enemy territory
and walk into a place where the cards
are stacked against you.
And the crowd is cheering
for the other opponent
and you were brought in to be beaten.
You were brought in
to be championed against.
I've done this walk a couple of times
and it changed me as a fighter.
[crowd cheering]
- This is your destiny.
Fuck this mother fucker's world up.
Let's go Dustin,
let's get to business.
[crowd howling and whistling]
[referee]Watch the take down.
hands up, chin down. Flurries. Fight!
[horn honking]
- *[Tim] Watch the kicks,
watch out lets go! *
*Watch the horn shot coming out.
Keep your jab hand up, buddy.*
*Good work! Good work! *
*Perfect, perfect. Protect with that
glove. Show him the power*
*Watch - he's ahead of you.
Heads up when you're throwing.*
*Touch him on the chin*
[punching] *Go for the throat!*
[crash on the floor] [crowd cheering]
- [Tim] Wazzup my baby,
wazzup my baby, wazzup my baby
- [Albert] I love it.
♪ [music] ♪
[announcer] *The winner by knock out.
Dustin Poirier!*
- [Albert] Beautiful!
- [Tim] Our main goal is not to
win titles,
win championships
and be the greatest.
We build better men
- *Four, three, two one.*
- [Coach] Albert Jordan, Alan Marg...
Say it well so I can hear you.
*Albert Stainback.? *
-I shot him.
[gong clanging]
[crowd clapping]
♪ [music] ♪
- *[announcer] Fighters to the middle
of the ring.*
- All right let's hear some noise for our fighters.
Lets Make some noise.
In the red corner.. Dustin Poirrier,
Albert Stainback, "Crazy" Tim Creuder,
Gil "The Thrill" Guillory,
"Bad" Chad Brousou, Corey Judice.
And in the blue corner. Paul Swallow,
Mike "The Truth" Jackson,
Joe Torres, Ronnie Lis,
Derrick "D-Rock" Krantz and
Dereck "The Sex Machine" Gauthier.
[foreign language]
♪ [music] ♪
And I'm your ring announcer,
Bob Moore